Rentt, if you're going to live here in Maalt,
you absolutely cannot refuse
a request from the Latours.
I have no intention of refusing.
But... is it okay?
Um... you're...
If they find out I'm a
monster, they'll kill me.
It's going to be hard.
No, when I met Isaac, he didn't
seem to care about my appearance.
If it was an issue, he wouldn't
have made the request at all.
All right.
But if there's any problem at all, tell me.
Of course. I'll start
by paying them a visit.
This place is incredible...
I like to think I have a good
sense of direction, but...
Hmm...
The sun won't help you. I suppose
that's enough of a hint.
There are very few places in the
labyrinths where you can see the sun.
Even without the sun to
guide them, an adventurer
can draw a mental map to guide them.
But if the map in my head was right, I
would've made it to the exit a long time ago...
This isn't the exit, I suppose.
Will you give up?
No, I'm going to keep
trying a little longer.
Or is that not okay?
Head that way, then.
Be warned, though, that the maze
will continue for a while.
If you'd like to take a break, why
don't you join me for a spot of tea?
I'll do that, then.
The Garden
Labyrinth
I assume she's a daughter
of the Latour family, then?
The teapot she's using is a
magic item, as well, I think...
I'm sorry, but did you forget
to put in the tea leaves?
This teapot can recreate the taste of any
tea that it's ever been used to brew.
That's an incredible item.
Where did you get it?
There are two types of magic items:
ones from the labyrinths,
and those made by craftsmen
to imitate the former.
This one was discovered 200
years ago in the labyrinths.
I believe it was worth around 300 platinum.
Platinum?
You could live a lifetime off of just one
platinum coin and have money left over!
And it cost 300 of them?
The Latour family is a lot wealthier
than most nobles, then...
It's more than worth it.
Adventurers risked their lives
in the labyrinths to find it.
You can risk your life in the labyrinths
and only end up with a bunch
of weird junk, though, too.
This is good!
I'm glad you like it.
I've recreated a tea I had long ago,
the one whose taste I liked best.
I see...
I've never had tea this good.
This may be rude, but is that
mask also a magic item?
Yeah...
I knew it!
Where did you get it?
Someone I know bought it from
a street stall in Maalt.
And for three bronze.
I had no idea there was something so
fascinating to be found in Maalt.
I'm sorry to ask, but...
Would you be willing to part with it?
I heard the Latours collect magic items.
Does she collect them, too?
I'm sorry. It's a valuable item, yes?
Of course, I'm more than willing
to pay what it's worth.
I'd love to sell it!
If I could only take it off...
But it's only thanks to this mask
that nobody can see I'm undead.
I'm sorry.
I can't do that.
No, I'm sure it must be an item
of great importance to you.
It was rude to ask.
No, don't worry about it.
Thank you for the tea.
Take care, then.
Yeah, thanks.
I'll give you a hint.
A hint?
You should avoid looking
at the sun, perhaps.
The sun, again?
I'll remember that.
There's definitely some trick to this maze.
The sun, huh?
Don't tell me...
Teleportation?
Can you go back?
No, there might be one-way teleporters.
I'm not even in a labyrinth... So
how could there be traps like this?
Which means...
I'm starting over?
I'm finally out.
Congratulations.
It seems you found the secret of the maze.
It's thanks to the advice
a certain someone gave me.
I'm Laura Latour, the head
of the Latour family.
A pleasure to make your acquaintance.
She's the head of the family?
I'm Rentt Vivie. A Bronze-class adventurer.
I came to discuss a job.
And...
I completed the maze.
Indeed you did.
Very few are capable of doing so.
Do I get a reward, too?
Of course you do.
Please choose any magic item you want
from the Latour Family's collection.
Then can you give me the
one that made that maze?
I'm sorry. I can't do that.
I was kidding.
Oh my.
You made me walk forever in that labyrinth.
It was my way of getting back at you.
You're a fascinating man.
Right this way.
Magic items made by human
hands are more consistently reliable.
But we can still only make the
simplest items, like these lights.
They're filled with mystery.
Just like the labyrinths.
Light.
Wow.
These are all magic items?
Yes. It was very difficult to get
them all cleaned up and organized.
No, that's not what I
meant... well, kind of.
How are all the labyrinths around
the world born? Why do they exist?
No one has ever found an answer.
The magic items are the same.
Just as you said, some of them are junk
that we have little idea how to use.
What is this item?
I don't know.
If you throw it, it will
continue to bounce forever.
Why did you collect all this stuff?
Because I wanted it.
That's what it means to
be an obsessive collector.
I see.
And this?
Have you ever seen the airships
they have in the west?
They're huge, and carry people
with the power of steam.
I've heard rumors.
It's a model of one of them.
It's powered by mana.
You can control it with this.
Is it fun?
Yes. I want it.
Then will you choose this?
I want it, but it's a toy, right?
The young boy inside me wants it, but...
The grown up inside me wants
something more useful.
You seem hesitant.
Rentt, focus your mind on the model.
What is this?
Amazing, is it not?
The controller can transfer
their mind into the model.
Yes, that's amazing...
But it burns a lot of mana.
I call it a "model", for
lack of a better term,
but this was discovered in the labyrinths.
Which means...
Yes. The airships are
modeled after this item.
Though they could never
figure out what made it fly,
and were forced to turn to other means.
I thought it was just a toy...
But it would be very helpful for scouting.
Yes.
But because of the way it uses mana,
you can't send it that far ahead.
True.
It couldn't go more than a
few minutes with my magic.
What will you do?
I'll think about it.
Take your time, then.
I will.
There's a lot ahead too, isn't there?
Is this a magic item as well?
Yes. It lights up when something approaches.
Anything?
Yes. It will react even to a rat.
Sounds useful, but I don't know
if it actually would be...
This seems to be a normal painting.
Press the button on the frame.
This?
Isn't it intriguing?
What do you think those voices are?
Is she just enjoying watching my reactions?
Rentt, be careful!
Isaac, where's the shutdown device?
We put it somewhere else, just to be safe.
You're kidding me...
Why is there a golem here?
Even I couldn't take a
hit from this thing...
Isaac, hurry!
Yes, of course.
Rentt, just try and hang
in there for a while!
It should be around here...
It's important to keep things organized.
Hey, how long can a golem stay powered?
It only took a little bit of my mana!
It only used your mana to activate!
That golem absorbs the mana and inorganic
matter in its surroundings to become stronger.
Can I hurt it a little?
I don't mind.
But you won't be able
to defeat it in battle.
I'm not planning on beating it.
Listen to me, Rentt.
Golems have a word in a magical tongue
on their forehead that means "truth."
You can add a single character
to change that word to "death,"
which will cause it to collapse.
There's nothing on its forehead at all!
At least, that's how they did
it in the very early days.
Normally they come with an
external shutdown device.
And if it doesn't have one?
Then you have to run, or defeat it.
Hey, have you found that shutdown device yet?
I'm pretty sure it was on this shelf...
Well, I can't keep this up any longer.
I didn't want to show anyone this
technique, but... I have no choice!
Mana-Spirit Fusion will do it!
Halt.
So they made it in time...
I'm so sorry! Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
My failure to properly manage our
magic items has put you in danger.
No, as your master, it's my fault.
No, it's my fault for carelessly
touching a magic item.
More importantly...
They're not gonna ask me
to pay for it, are they?
I'll have the servants clean this up later.
Now, what magic item will you choose?
If you don't mind, I'd like to continue.
What's that?
Materials taken from monsters.
They're not magic items, but they can be used to make medicine and weapons.
Materials taken from monsters?
Does that catch your interest?
It's the blood of a vampire.
Ingesting the blood of a vampire is
said to make one a vampire themself.
Is that true?
It's just a rumor.
There are quite a few records of
people drinking vampire blood.
Most of them went mad and died.
The few who survived are said to have become
hollow shells of their former selves.
So nobody was ever able to
become a vampire, then?
Do you think anyone would ever
say they've become a vampire?
They would immediately be killed.
True.
So there's just rumors, and nothing more.
But even rumors are enough to make it
desired among those who wish for eternal life.
You can sell it for a fortune
to the high nobility.
I've made my choice.
And this is what you chose?
Yes.
Yes, it's wonderful.
I've seen airships, but I had no idea
they were inspired by a magic item.
And not only can you control
it, you can see what it sees?
It's a ton of fun.
Who are the Latour family, though?
They're freer with gifts than many royals.
Well, there aren't many
adventurers like me
who make regular trips
to the Tarasque swamp.
I can really take this, too?
Yes. It's thanks for taking
on such a troublesome job.
Of course, we'll pay you what's on the job
sheet each time you complete the task.
I see.
Now I can devote myself
fully to caring for Laura.
So, you want to try it?
Of course... but I think first it's
time to stop playing and face reality.
I wasn't just playing...
Was he to your liking?
Is that how it seems to you?
Yes.
He was a rare sort of guest.
I'm afraid I let myself get too excited.
It was a nice change of pace.
But for now,
please get some rest.
It's safe to assume this is real?
I'm pretty sure it is.
When I saw this, I could feel it.
If I drink this, I knew,
something would change.
Something instinctive?
But are you sure?
Just as Laura Latour said,
the records say that everyone who ingests
vampire blood meets a terrible end...
So it seems.
It's rare for you to be hesitant.
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't scared.
I know I need this if I'm going to evolve.
My body wants it.
But it's too dangerous.
You may not survive.
Even if your undead body can take it, you...
If you can avoid drinking
it, I'd prefer you don't.
I wouldn't mind you being an undead forever.
Just stay here forever and spend
your life as an adventurer.
Lorraine...
But that's not what you want, is it?
Even if you don't have the talent,
even if it takes you years...
You want to become one
no matter what, right?
A Mythril-class adventurer...
Rentt Faina